翻译  艾瑞卡
翻译  面条打包子
翻译  吃货丁小七
翻译  杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译  香茗小焙
翻译  草草
翻译  小饭
时间轴  萌
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
俄语顾问   西摆
校对  草草
总监  草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第六集
再来点水吗  夫人
More water, ma'am?
好的
Yes, please.
还要多久能到  本
How much longer, Ben?
预计还有4小时16分钟
Estimated four hours and 16 minutes.
来点早餐吗  跟往常一样
Some breakfast, maybe? The usual?
那太好了  谢谢你
That would be wonderful. Thank you.
还有一小时就日出了
Only about an hour until sunrise.
看北极光的最后机会了
Last chance for those Northern Lights.
我可以跟你讲
I could tell you about
在电影院工作  送报纸什么的
working at a movie theater, some paper route.
蹬着自行车骑五里路
Riding my bicycle five miles
为了一个月十美金  给七家送报纸
to deliver seven papers for ten dollars a month, but...
但事实是  我没有自行车
the truth is, I didn't have a bicycle,
比起检票我更多时间是花在
and I spent more time sneaking into the movie theater
溜进放映厅看电影
than tearing tickets.
那究竟是什么
So what was it, then?
我的第一份工作吗  那不能写进书里
My first job? Oh, that can't go in the book.
为什么不行
Why not?
我给一个在林子里种印度大麻的人打工
I worked for a man who grew cannabis in the back woods.
大麻贩子吗
A weed dealer?
不是  种地的  亨利叔叔
No, a farmer. Uncle Henry.
不是我亲叔叔  只是所有人都这么叫他
He wasn't my uncle, but that's just what everybody called him.
那你替亨利叔叔做什么
What did you do for Uncle Henry?
我装货
I packaged the product.
不知怎么他信任我做称重
For some reason, he trusted me with the scales.
那你  有没有揩油
And did you... partake of the product?
没有  老好人亨利叔叔
No. Good old Uncle Henry,
他用自己的化粪池给作物施肥
he fertilized his crop from his own septic tank.
但工作不错  我攒了不少钱
But it was a good job, though. I saved up a lot of money.
我在桑蒂诺四年的书费
It's how I bought all my books
就是这么攒下来的
my entire four years at The Sentinel.
跟我讲讲桑蒂诺
Tell me about The Sentinel.
你的第一份工作是什么
What was your first job?
别岔开话题  这书不是讲我的
No, no. Book's not about me.
《天蝎》里的男妓
The hustler in Scorpio.
那是你吧
That was you, wasn't it?
为什么这么觉得
What makes you think that?
作家不是都写自己熟悉的事吗
Don't writers write what they know?
男妓的原型是我的一个朋友
The hustler's based on a friend of mine.
我不接客
I didn't turn tricks.
只是在酒店大堂等着
I just... waited in the hotel lobbies
以防他惹上麻烦
in case he got into trouble.
挺艰苦的少年生活啊
Tough life for a teenager.
总比露宿街头好
Better than digging around in dumpsters.
他后来怎么样了  你的朋友
What happened to him? Your friend?
他死了
He died.
跟书里一样死于艾滋吗
Was it AIDS, like in the book?
自杀
Suicide.
书里怎么不这么写
Why didn't you write it that way?
因为那是小说
Because it was fiction.
因为自杀太自私
Because... suicide is too selfish.
稍后再聊
Let's talk later.
我有些事得跟克莱尔谈谈
I have a few things I gotta run over with Claire.
好的
Sure.
安排很紧
It's a tight schedule,
可能在回程之前都说不上话了
so we may not be able to speak until the flight back.
没事  第一次去莫斯科
No worries. First time in Moscow.
我还想去高尔基公园和天鹅湖呢
I've got a date with Gorky Park and Swan Lake.
进展如何
How's it going?
凯茜把声明发邮件给我了
Cathy emailed me the statement.
我们让克林姆林宫缓和了措辞
We got the Kremlin to tone down the language.
你觉得科里根会说吗
Do you think Corrigan will say it?
他肯定会恨里面每一个字  但如果能回家
I'm sure he'll hate every word, but if it means coming home...
佩特罗夫肯考虑这事的唯一原因
The only reason that Petrov is considering this is
就是我们在联合国有筹码
because we have leverage in the UN.
你们都确定这事没问题吗
You're both confident that this is rock solid?
要是佩特罗夫不配合  等我们一到美国
If Petrov doesn't cooperate, the Secretary-General
联合国秘书长就会立即召开紧急会议
will call an emergency session the moment we land in the States.
但愿不用走这条路
Let's hope we don't have to play that card.
但不要让步太多
Just don't give too much away.
他这段时间在安理会受到排挤
Oh, listen, he's been marginalized in the Security Council,
他扣押了一名美国公民
he's detaining an American citizen,
他也想洗白
he wants to wash his hands of.
我相信我们这回能遇到一个比之前来访华盛顿
I think we'll find that we're dealing with a much more reasonable man
更通情达理的总统
than the one that visited Washington.
我们会带着维和协议和科里根一起回来
We fly back with a peacekeeping deal and Corrigan.
把困境变成美事
Lemons to lemonade.
回程的时候把我们的套间给科里根住吧
I think we should give Corrigan our suite on the way back,
别让媒体去打扰他
give him some privacy from the press.
可以  好主意
Yeah, that's a good idea.
-你有睡过吗  -没有
- Have you slept at all? - No.
-吃过了吗  -还没
- Eaten anything? - Not yet.
给
Here.
看这个
Come see this.
是不是这世上最摄人心魄的风景
Isn't it the most beautiful thing you've ever seen?
别发呆了  麦克斯
Earth to Max.
你好像有点心不在焉
You seem distracted.
是啊  可能有点
Yeah, maybe a little.
是因为凯拉吗
Is it Kara?
凯拉  什么啊
Kara? What?
你应该约她出去  她会答应的
You should ask her out. I know she'd say yes.
这对你有好处  结识新的人
It'd be good for you. Meet new people.
我不能  我还不信任自己
I can't. I don't trust myself yet.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
麦克斯
Hey, Max.
说吧
Tell me.
你保证不会看扁我
You promise you won't judge?
我不会的  我保证
I won't, I promise.
她离开我之后
Well, after she left,
有很长一段时间我沉迷于毒品和性
there were a lot of nights of drugs and women.
有些女人我根本都不记得
And some of the women, I don't even remember.
而凯拉是个好女孩  所以
And Kara's a nice girl, so...
但你已经洗心革面了
But you're not that person anymore.
之前有几次挺危险的
There were some dangerous situations.
情况很糟糕
It was all really fucked up
而且我没每次都采取保护措施
and I wasn't always safe.
你去检查过吗
Well, have you gotten tested?
没
No.
那你得去检查下
Well, then you need to be tested.
我知道  但我不敢去
I know, but it scares the shit out of me.
是啊  你想让我陪你去吗
Well, sure. Do you want me to go with you?
不  不用
No, I don't.
陶森市有家免费诊所
There's a free clinic in Towson.
我好多朋友都去那儿看病
Plenty of my friends go there.
-你就直接过去  -知道了  知道了
- You just walk in... - I get it! I get it.
我明天可以陪你一起去  如果你想的话
I could go with you tomorrow if you want me to.
我不需要你教我怎么做
I don't need a mother.
我不是在对你说教
Hey, I'm not trying to mother you.
我只是  我关心你  希望你平安
I just-- I care about you and I want you to be safe.
你就
Just--
麦克斯
Max.
Max!
非常感谢
Большое спасибо.
谢谢你释放科里根先生
Thank you for releasing Mr. Corrigan.
这对我们意义重大
It means a great deal to us.
对他的爱人肯定也意义重大
And I'm sure a great deal to his loved ones.
我们拥有相同的诉求  这只是个开始
We all want the same things. This is just a first step.
我的幕僚长利特斯基先生会护送你去监狱
Mr. Litsky, my Chief of Staff, will escort you to the facilities.
-请吧  -总统先生请
- Shall we? - Mr. President.
-谢谢  -你先请
- Thank you. - After you.
那我们重新开始
So... we start over.
就好像这是我们第一次见面
As though we meet for the first time.
请坐
Please.
-保证他会建一座监狱  -监狱
- Promise him a prison. - A prison?
一座新的联邦监狱
A brand new federal corrections facility.
他的选民为什么会希望选区里住进罪犯
Why would his constituents want convicts in their backyard?
他们不希望
They don't.
但他们希望选区里有更多工作
They do want jobs in their backyard.
多年来他一直在争取联邦政府的拨款
He's been trying to get federal funding for years.
博奇一直否决他的申请
Birch has fought him on it.
告诉他你能让博奇回心转意
Tell him you'll get Birch to come around.
如果这说服不了他
If that doesn't work,
暗示说有可能任命他为交通部长
hint there might be a place for him as Transportation Secretary.
他是汽车产业的代言人
He's owned by the auto industry.
他在二氧化碳排放问题上的立场简直气人
His stance on carbon emissions is deplorable.
那就用环保署署长的人选来制衡他
Then balance him out with whoever you have running the EPA.
现在就定下内阁人选我觉得为时过早
I am not ready to make cabinet commitments this early on.
这不是定下人选  你只是愿意考虑他
It's not a commitment. You're just open to considering him.
道格  得开始了
Doug? We should get started.
把汽车产业转化为你的优势
Use the auto industry to your advantage.
不论温考斯基支持谁
Whoever Winkowski supports,
福特和克莱斯勒的所有超级代表都会跟随他
every superdelegate backed by Ford and Chrysler follows.
如果这还没用
And if that doesn't work,
告诉他你交通部长的候选人里有迪克·巴特勒
tell him you're considering Dick Butler for Transportation.
他讨厌巴特勒
He hates Butler.
我得挂了  告诉我他的答复
I gotta go. Let me know what he says.
你来是为了锻炼身体  而不是工作
You're here to work on your body, not work on your work.
上司打来的
When the boss calls...
你现在由我负责  我说了算
Well, while you're on my turf, I'm the boss.
快进去躺到垫子上
Let's get in there and lie down on the mat.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
-迈克尔  -安德伍德夫人
- Michael. - Mrs. Underwood.
叫我克莱尔就好
Claire.
他们对你好吗
You've been treated well?
很好  如您所见
Very well, as you can see.
谢谢  利特斯基先生
Thank you, Mr. Litsky,
但我想听科里根先生自己说
but I'd like to hear it from Mr. Corrigan.
是的  他们对我很好
Yes, they've treated me well.
-你看过医生吗  -昨天看过
- You've seen a doctor? - I have. Yesterday.
-你看起来很瘦  -我一直很瘦
- You look thin. - I've always been thin.
总统让我亲自过来
The president asked me to see you in person
告诉你这个好消息
to share the good news.
你的释放条款已经敲定了
The terms of your release have been finalized.
我们明天就带你回家
We'll be bringing you home with us tomorrow.
我以为你会高兴
I thought you'd be pleased.
条款是什么
What are the terms?
我们会举行联合新闻发布会
There will be a joint press conference.
-跟佩特罗夫吗  -是的  两位总统一起
- With Petrov? - Yes, both presidents.
协议要求你做一个简短声明
The agreement asks that you make a brief statement.
抱歉  字太小  我也没戴眼镜
I'm sorry, um, the type is too small and I don't have glasses.
-我们为科里根先生提供了眼镜  -是的
- We offered glasses to Mr. Corrigan-- - They did.
我的在被拘捕时弄坏了
Mine broke during the arrest.
其他犯人没有眼镜
The other inmates don't get glasses.
我不想受特殊待遇
I didn't want special treatment.
我们为所有需要的人提供眼镜  不论国际
We provide glasses to anyone who needs them, Russian or American.
这是个谎言
That is a lie.
我读给你听
I will read it.
上面写着  "我  迈克尔·科里根
It says, "I, Michael Corrigan,
就违反俄罗斯联邦法律
apologize to the citizens of the Russian Federation
向俄国公民道歉
for breaking your laws.
我不该向未成年人
I regret my part in exposing minors
宣扬非传统性取向
to nontraditional sexual attitudes.
我很感谢佩特罗夫总统
I am grateful to President Petrov
宽容地释放了我
for the clemency my release demonstrates,
并允许我回到美国"
and for allowing me to return to the United States."
谁写的
Who wrote it?
这是国务院
It's the result of extended negotiations
与俄罗斯外交部之间
between representatives of the State Department
深入谈判后的结果
and the Russian Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
抱歉  我不能做这个声明
I'm sorry, I can't say it.
我知道情况很不理想  迈克尔
I know it's far from ideal, Michael.
除非废除法律  不然不可能理想
There is no ideal. Other than repealing the law.
能让我们单独待会儿吗
May we have a moment?
佩特罗夫总统让我陪着您
President Petrov asked me to remain with you.
我请你让我们单独待一会儿
And I'm asking you to give us a moment.
利特斯基先生  这间牢房被监听了吧
Mr. Litsky? I'm assuming this cell is bugged?
我对这里并不了解
I know nothing about the facilities.
-在哪里  -安德伍德夫人
- Where is it? - Mrs. Underwood.
科里根先生和我要想真正地单独谈话
If Mr. Corrigan and I are to speak privately,
我需要保证对话的私密性
I would like to be assured that it is truly private.
告诉我监听设备在哪里
Show me where the bug is.
进来
Подойти.
安德伍德夫人要求拆掉监听器
Госпожа Андервуд просила убрать микрофон.
如果可以的话  这就拆
Прямо сейчас, если можно.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们不可能废除法律
They're not going to repeal the law.
你必须发表声明才能被释放
The statement is a prerequisite for your release.
没有商量的余地了  迈克尔
There are no negotiations here, Michael.
谈判已经结束了
That part already happened.
其他27个人呢
What about the 27 others?
他们不是美国人
They're not American.
如果不释放他们  我也不该被释放
Well, if they're not gonna be released, neither should I.
对于他们我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do for them.
你是第一夫人  还是美国驻联合国大使
You're the First Lady, and the ambassador to the United Nations.
你却告诉我你无能为力
And you're telling me there's nothing you can do?
我不相信
I refuse to believe that.
迈克尔  争取到你的释放就已经很艰难了
Michael, it was hard enough to negotiate just for your release.
恐怕你得把我拖出去了
You'll have to drag me out of here
因为我不会做那个声明
because I'm not giving that statement.
这只是几句话
It's just words.
等一回到美国本土  你就可以否认这些话
Words you can disown the moment you're back on US soil.
佩特罗夫的反同法
Petrov's gay propaganda law?
那也只是言语
That's just words, too.
指挥与控制权的轮换
So, command and control rotation.
第一年之后每半年一次
Semi-annually, after the first year.
我们希望能立即轮换
We pushed for immediate rotation,
-可是以色列人...  -当然
- but the Israelis have-- - No, of course.
我们需要赢得他们的信任
We need to earn their trust.
但是  做出任何重大决定之前
But we would never make any major decisions
我们都会先跟你的上将商量
without consulting your generals first.
只要能保证透明性  保持沟通就好
As long as there is transparency and communication.
这正是整个项目的关键
Well, that's the key to this entire enterprise.
只要平安度过第一年
Then after the first year is fine and, uh...
驻军数量也合适
troop numbers look agreeable,
你能保证派来这个数目吗
are you sure you can procure this many on your end?
是的  我不需要通过国会
Yes. I don't need Congress for that.
的确  但资金怎么解决
No, but the funding.
与其他派驻一样从国防预算里拨
It comes out of the DOD budget like any regular deployment.
至于你方军队的基础设施建设和后勤
Now, infrastructure and logistical supplies for your troops,
这份支出可以算作辅助设施
well, we can add that expense as ancillary support.
我们能出点
We can pitch in.
不管你们能拿出多少我们当然都欢迎
Well, whatever you could spare would certainly be welcome.
不过还有一件我们都在考虑的事
But... that brings us to the elephant in the room.
导弹防御
Missile defense.
我能接受波兰那边的部分削减
Now, I can accept a partial scale-back in Poland.
这可以不公开
And it doesn't have to be... announced.
可我们得考虑捷克方面
But we need to consider the Czech Republic.
说说你的顾虑
Tell me your concerns.
我说了不要打断我们
Я просил нас не беспокоить.
你夫人很重视隐私啊
Your wife values privacy.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我们正谈导弹防御呢
We were talking missile defense.
怎么提起克莱尔了
Why did you bring up Claire?
她正与科里根密谈  没什么大不了的
She's... talking privately to Corrigan. It's no matter.
出什么问题了吗
Is there something wrong?
希望没有
I hope not.
回到导弹防御上来吧
Now, missile defense.
就是一份说给俄国媒体听的声明而已
A statement for the Russian media. That's all it is.
我问你
Let me ask you something.
你要是我的话  会读这份声明吗
Would you read that statement if you were me?
是的  我会读的
Yes, I would.
你会感谢一个说你对孩子有威胁的人
You'd thank a man who says you're dangerous to children?
不必出自真心  只需说出来
You don't have to mean it. You just have to say it.
我绝食抗议了六天
I went on a hunger strike for six days.
然后我停了下来
Then I stopped.
饥饿使我难以坚持
Too hungry. I couldn't go on.
跟我一起被捕的  有个叫塞尔盖的
One of the others that, uh, I was arrested with, Sergei,
他坚持了28天
hung in there for 28 days.
他们决定强迫他进食
They decided to force-feed him,
并终于同意他母亲看望他
and they finally agreed to let his mother visit.
可这都太晚了
Turns out it was too late, on both counts.
关于我的新闻铺天盖地
Lots of news stories about me.
却没有关于塞尔盖的
None about Sergei.
一个人就这么悄无声息地死了
A man dies and it's like nothing happened.
就因为他是俄国人
Because he's Russian.
我不能抛弃其他被捕的人
I can't abandon the others in here.
还有外面成千上万
Or the millions of people out there
被人说他们生来就有问题的人
who are told the way they are born is wrong.
但回家后你可以讲出塞尔盖的故事
But back home, you can share Sergei's story.
这对他或其他人无济于事
That doesn't do anything for him or the others.
如果有必要  我们会把你拖出去
We will drag you out if necessary.
在这事上你无力反抗
You don't have any power over that.
但是  我可以自主的
But the one thing I do have power over
是不发表这份声明
is not making that statement.
好吧
Okay.
那如果我让他们修改
What if I can get them to change the line
关于非传统性取向这句呢
about nontraditional sexual attitudes?
这才是最困扰你的部分  对吧
That's what bothers you most, right?
这不是文字游戏  要么做到底  要么不做
You can't parse this. It's all or nothing.
政治不是这么搞的
That's not how politics works.
但革命都是这样的
But it's how revolution works!
进展怎么样了
How are things going?
我能跟你说句话吗
May I speak with you for a moment?
如果达不成一致  那就算了  就这样
Что если не будет согласования. То и будет и пусть. Все.
-你有什么目的  -你指什么
- What are you up to? - What do you mean?
科里根
Corrigan.
告诉我发生什么了
Tell me what's wrong.
你就希望他拒绝  从而使我难堪
You wanted him to refuse. To embarrass me.
你夫人叫他拒绝发表声明
Your wife told him not to make the statement.
简直荒唐
That is ludicrous.
你是带着虚情假意而来
You came here with false intentions.
不  维克多  我们都料到他会很顽固
No. Viktor, we knew that he might be stubborn.
但此人毕竟信念坚定
But this is a man with strong beliefs.
这份声明对我意义重大
This statement is important to me.
克莱尔肯定正努力说服他发表声明
Well, if anything, Claire is trying to convince him to make it.
那为什么她要求把监听设备拿走
Then why did she ask for the surveillance audio to be removed?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许是想让他放松
Perhaps so he wouldn't feel on the spot.
但是  不用担心这些
But, look, I wouldn't worry about this just yet.
克莱尔很有说服力
Claire is very persuasive.
我把话说明白
Let me be very clear.
他不发表声明  任何协议都免谈
If there is no statement, there is no deal on any front.
我们的协议  关于他的协议都取消
Not between us. Not for him.
他会接受审判  被定罪  被判决
He gets tried, convicted, sentenced.
我已经让利特斯基先生通知他们了
Now, I asked Mr. Litsky to inform them both.
我对我妻子信心十足
I have complete confidence in my wife.
维克多  你要清楚  这不是什么计划的一部分
And Viktor, you must know, this isn't part of any plan.
就这样
That's it.
这份声明没有讨价还价的余地
There's no flexibility with regard to the statement.
你不配合就得接受审判
You don't cooperate, you go to trial.
正好  他们不能阻止我在法庭上发声
Good. They can't keep me from speaking in court.
那你丈夫怎么办
What about your husband?
你和约翰谈过了
You've spoken to John?
我跟他说我们抱很大希望
I let him know we were hopeful.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
他本想跟我们一起来
He wanted to come with us,
但这明显不可能
but that wasn't possible, for obvious reasons.
我保证见过你就给他打电话
I promised to call after I saw you.
我其实想让你在空军一号上亲自给他打电话
I was thinking... you'd call instead. From Air Force One.
他会明白的
He'll understand.
他很想你  迈克尔
He misses you, Michael.
我也想他  我想念很多东西
I miss him. I miss a lot of things.
我的父母  我的朋友们  我的狗
My parents. My friends. My dog.
牢房外的明媚阳光
More than two square feet of sunlight.
但这就是我们选择的生活
But it's the life we chose.
我们正是因此才走到一起的
It's what our bond is built on.
约翰在国内媒体上非常活跃
John has been very vocal back home.
一直在呼吁释放你
All he talks about is your release.
你在让他痛苦  而你没必要这样做
You're causing him pain. And you don't have to.
他当初也没必要与我结婚
And he didn't have to marry me.
-这话太自私了  -或许吧
- That's selfish. - Maybe.
但为了离开这间牢房就否认我信仰的一切
But so is contradicting everything I believe in
也同样自私
just to get out of this cell.
我认为你现在这样做更加自私
I think what you're doing is more selfish.
这是你的自尊心在作祟
It's about ego.
你想向自己证明一些事
Proving something to yourself.
被你留在家里的那个男人却因此而痛苦
And a man back home is hurting because of it.
约翰的意志很薄弱  换他在这里待几天
John is weak. He'd say the statement in a heartbeat
肯定会毫不犹豫地读那份声明
if he spent more than a few days in here,
这也正是我在这里而他不在的原因
which is why I'm here and he's not.
如果他认为我这是自私  那又如何
If he thinks I'm being selfish, so what?
随便他能不能接受
Either he accepts it or he doesn't.
这不正是婚姻的意义吗
Isn't that what marriage is about?
接受你配偶的自私
Accepting your partner's selfishness?
你最应该理解这一点吧
You of all people should understand.
你根本不了解婚姻
You know nothing about marriage.
你认为婚姻的意义是...自我牺牲吗
You think it's about... sacrifice?
我认为婚姻的意义是彼此尊重
I think it's about respect.
而你没有尊重他的痛苦
And you're not respecting his pain.
他的痛苦无关紧要
His pain doesn't matter.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that?
因为我的痛苦也无关紧要
Because mine doesn't either.
你知道自绝食抗议以来
You know what I've been asking myself
我一直在问自己什么问题吗
ever since the hunger strike?
"我真的愿意为此去死吗"
Am I truly willing to die for this?
我不知道这个问题的答案
I don't know the answer to that question.
但至少有一件事能让我足够在乎
But at least I have something that I care enough about
以至于问得出这样的问题
to even ask the question.
你这样问过你自己吗
Have you asked that of yourself?
你愿意为何而死
What are you willing to die for?
您准备离开了吗  安德伍德夫人
Are you ready yet, Mrs. Underwood?
还没有
Not yet.
恕我问一下  还要多久
How much longer, if I might?
请通知总统先生
Please inform the President
科里根先生跟我走之前我是不会离开的
I won't be leaving until Mr. Corrigan comes with me.
您不能留在这里  安德伍德夫人
You can't stay here, Mrs. Underwood--
请转达我的话  好吗
Pass along the message, would you?
我们不能让第一夫人留在...
We can't have the First Lady staying--
你不能强行让我离开
You're not going to forcibly remove me.
所以请照我说的去做
So, please, do as I ask.
你在干什么  维克多都快气疯了
What are you doing? Viktor is beside himself.
你得说服他放弃那份声明
You need to convince him to let go of the statement.
你得考虑到可能有人在监听我们的谈话
Look, you have to assume we're being overheard.
这电话可不是保密线路
This is not a secure line.
我所说的话完全可以当着佩特罗夫的面说
Anything I'm saying, I'd say to Petrov himself if he were here.
我以为你在劝说科里根做声明呢
I thought you were convincing Corrigan to make the statement.
弗兰西斯  我在尽一切努力
Francis, I'm doing my best,
但我们必须两边一起努力
but we need to come at this from both sides.
他很固执
Well, he's adamant.
他不会让步  而且我也不怪他
He's not gonna back down and I don't blame him.
科里根也很固执
Corrigan's adamant, too.
整个协议都取决于这件事
The entire deal hinges on this.
维克多把他的要求说得很明确
Now, Viktor made it very clear what his needs are,
而且我们之前也保证过...
and we made promises before we--
我正在努力挽回局面
I'm trying to salvage the situation.
没多少时间了
There isn't much time.
我们定好了明天回到飞机上
We're scheduled to get back on the plane tomorrow
媒体都等着迈克尔也上飞机
and the press expects Michael to get on with us.
维克多  如果你正在听
Viktor, if you're listening to this,
请明白我一直在为你说话
please know I'm advocating on your behalf.
但你或许应该考虑放弃这份声明
But you might want to consider letting the statement go.
他不会那样做的  克莱尔
He's not gonna do it, Claire.
好好和他谈谈  弗兰西斯
Just talk to him, Francis.
如果他不愿放弃
If he won't let it go,
看能不能把语言再缓和一些
see if he'll tone it down some more.
他也不希望这一切功亏一篑
He doesn't want all of this to fall apart either.
好吧  我尽力试试
All right. I'll see what I can do.
有消息我会通知你的
I'll keep you posted.
这太好了  谢谢
Oh, this is great. Thank you.
能给我一张收据吗
If I could have a receipt...
-不好意思  -谢谢
- Oh. Excuse me. Sorry. - I appreciate it.
麦克斯
Hey, Max.
我在诊所
I'm here at the clinic.
你没事吧  你听起来...
Are you okay? You sound--
我好害怕  他们马上要抽血了
I'm scared. They're about to take the blood sample.
你能来吗
Can you come?
求你了  我真的好害怕  丽萨
Please, I'm really scared, Lisa.
好的  好的  我尽快赶过去  好吗
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I'll be there as soon as I can, okay?
嗯  等着我
Yeah. Just hold tight.
我得离开  你能照看一下这里吗
Hey, um, I need to go. Do you mind taking care of all this?
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
好消息  奥尔西先生  你所有检测均呈阴性
Good news, Mr. Orsay. You're negative on all fronts.
这是检测结果  供您保留
There are the results, for your records.
这里还有一些小册子  关于保护措施
I've got some literature if you like, on protection,
防护举措  如何避免高危接触
preventative strategies, how to avoid high-risk encounters.
谢谢  不用了
No, thank you, I'm... I'm good.
那个  我还是拿着吧
Yeah, actually, I will take those.
是阳性
I'm positive.
我现在不想一个人待着
I just I can't-- I can't be alone right now.
跟我来  跟我来吧
Come with me. Come with me. Okay?
-斯坦普  -你真厉害
- Stamper. - You're good.
他答应了
He said yes?
耗了几小时  但他加入了
Took a couple of hours, but he's on board.
你提到巴特勒了吗
Did you have to bring up Butler?
-监狱就够了  -太好了
- The prison was enough. - Great.
接下来你要谁
Who's your next target?
威利斯·莫里森  12区
Willis Morrison, Twelfth District.
俄亥俄  他的资料在我家
Ohio. I have his file at home.
我一小时后打给你
I'll call you in an hour.
稀罕啊  你又在打电话
Surprise, surprise. You're on the phone again.
这是我自由时间  不归你管了
I'm on my time now, not yours.
你要走吗
You outta here?
嗯  你是我最后一个预约
Yeah, you were my last appointment.
今天的复健有什么用吗
Did that work today help?
嗯  我感觉很棒
It did. I feel great.
你的进步很大
Well, you're making great progress.
等你完全恢复了
And when you're fully recovered, you know,
我们会做手术把粘在你耳朵上的手机切除掉
we'll have that cell phone surgically removed from your ear.
回见了
See you later.
但我来说不是更有力吗
But isn't it even more powerful coming from me?
会很空洞  那些话必须他说
It would ring hollow. The words must come from him.
反正也没人会相信他是真心
But no one will believe he means them, anyway.
他是否真心无所谓
Whether he means them doesn't matter.
但如果他说了  就表明他尊重我们的法律
The fact that he says them shows respect for our laws.
我也希望他能发表声明
I wish he'd make the damn statement too,
他或许会的  但如果他不肯
and maybe he will. But if he doesn't,
你就愿让我们今天
you're willing to let all the work
达成的一切协议都付诸东流吗
we've accomplished today go down the drain
就因为一个大嘴巴抗议者
because of one loud-mouth protester
和一项你肯定也并不认同的法律吗
over a law you can't possibly believe in?
你说得对  我是不认同
No, you're right. I don't believe in it.
我两个内阁成员还是同性恋呢
Two of my cabinet ministers are gay.
我前妻的侄子也是
My ex-wife's nephew is gay,
那孩子我视如己出
the one who is basically like a son to me.
我个人根本不在乎
Personally, I don't care.
既然你不在乎
So if you don't care,
就让我们带他离开监狱  上飞机吧
let's haul him out and put him on the plane.
听我说  我也不希望我们的协议泡汤
Look, I don't want our deal to fall apart any more than you do.
你妻子在电话上说得对
Your wife was right on the phone.
但我要考虑的不仅是我们的协议
But there is more than just our deal for me to consider.
我得显示出力量
I need to show strength.
不会有人将此视为软弱
No one's going to see this as a weakness.
恰恰相反  你放他走只会受到赞誉
On the contrary, you'll be applauded for letting him go.
谁的赞誉  西方吗
By who? Hm? The West?
你根本不了解俄罗斯  总统先生
You don't understand Russia, Mr. President.
如果大家不喜欢你的工作表现
If people don't like the job you're doing,
他们就会把你赶下台
they vote you out of office.
如果他们不喜欢我的工作表现  他们会推翻塑像
If they don't like the job I'm doing, they topple statues.
流血争斗  天下大乱
Blood is spilled. Chaos takes over.
反同法是不是很无理  是的
Is the gay propaganda law barbaric? Yes.
当然了
Of course it is.
但宗教  传统
But religion, tradition,
对大部分国民  那深入骨髓
for most of my people, it's in their bones.
这项法律  是为他们而出台
This law was passed for them.
我得像你那样  代表人民的意愿
I have to represent my people the same way you do.
如果科里根不为自己的行为付出代价
And if there is no cost to Corrigan's actions,
很多人会感到遭背叛
many of my people will feel betrayed.
不会因为你放了一个人  就引发革命
There won't be a revolution because you freed one man.
革命是一点点  一步步兴起的
Revolution sneaks up on you, one small step at a time.
我不能冒险  即使是很微小的一步
I don't take chances, even with the smallest of steps.
第一夫人一到  全员出动啊
No stone left unturned when the First Lady's in town.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
能把盐递给我吗
If you pass the salt.
你是如何变成今天这样的
How did Michael Corrigan become Michael Corrigan?
-同性恋吗  -活动家
- Gay? - An activist.
联调局一定给你介绍情况了吧
I'm sure you got a briefing from the FBI.
是的  但我想听你说
Yes, but I would like to hear it from you.
早在90年代初期  我一个朋友
A friend of mine, and this is in the early '90s,
她请我去参加一个社区集会
she invited me to go with her to a community organizing meeting.
我闲来无事  就去了
I had nothing better to do, so I said okay.
我们去了  屋里至多就12个人吧
We get there and there's maybe 12 people in the room, tops.
那场面真的很可怜
It was pretty sad, actually.
而演讲人的讲话主题是垃圾
And the guy speaking is talking about garbage.
-垃圾  -废物回收
- Garbage? - Recycling.
这家伙让所有12人都昏昏欲睡
And the guy is putting all 12 of us to sleep.
他说的话确实有道理  但毫无号召力
What he was saying made sense, but... zero charisma.
甚至可以说是排斥力
It was worse: anti-charisma.
但我注意到他有一个习惯
But I noticed he had this habit of, uh...
当他说到重点时会歪头
tilting his head when he was making an important point.
真的很惹人爱
It was... it was so endearing.
就像这样
It was like this.
像这样
Like...
我无法控制自己  当场就爱上了他
I couldn't help it. I fell in love with him right then and there.
演讲人是约翰
This was John?
真是恍如隔世
A long time ago, in a galaxy far, far away.
电视上的他挺有号召力的
Well, he's pretty charismatic on TV.
他学会了如何号召别人  我学会了如何思考
He learned charisma. I learned how to think.
我们互相磨合得不错
We rubbed off on each other well.
我不知道你们在一起这么久了
I didn't know you'd been together so long.
21年
Twenty-one years.
只结婚了五年  因为之前我们没法结
Only been married for five because, well, we couldn't earlier.
弗兰西斯和我刚庆祝完28周年结婚纪念日
Francis and I just celebrated 28.
超过你半辈子了
Over half your life.
没错  我还从未这么想过
That's true. I haven't even thought about that.
你结婚时还很年轻
You were young.
22岁
Twenty-two.
你后悔过吗
You ever regret it?
不  不后悔  我爱弗兰西斯
No. No. I love Francis.
如今更甚以往
Now more than ever.
我后悔了
I regret it.
在还未完全了解自己之前就与人定下终身
Committing to someone before I even knew who I was.
我们并未进行合法宣誓
We didn't take legal vows,
但我们有自己的方式
but we had our own version.
-真的很傻  -为什么
- Stupid. - Why?
因为我给他的就只有伤害
Because all I've ever done is hurt him.
让他待在我背后  劈腿  各种各样
Um, kept him in my shadow, cheated on him, you name it.
两人相濡以沫的岁月最重要
Well, it's the history that counts,
而非其他事情  对吧
not the other things, right?
没错  过去无可替代
That's true. No substitute for history.
但对他不公平
But it's unfair to him.
我不相信公平
I don't believe in fairness.
我认为你也不相信  即便你在为之奋斗
I don't think you do either, even though you fight for it.
我不相信你对你丈夫的爱更甚以往
And I don't believe you love your husband more than ever.
你怎么知道
How could you possibly know?
将心比心
Takes one to know one.
约翰和我已经两年没上过床了
John and I haven't slept with each other in almost two years.
我们甚至都分房睡了
We don't even sleep in the same bedroom.
我们谈过分居的事  但终究没那么做
We've talked about separating, but we never follow through.
为了婚姻平等努力至今  我们自己却离婚了
It seems wrong to fight this hard for marriage equality
感觉不太好
and then get divorced.
于事业无益
Bad for business.
说实话  我认为这违背人性
Honestly, I don't think it's how humans are built.
在一起五十年  白头偕老
To be with each other for 50 years.
你也没得选  对吧
You don't have that option either, do you?
什么意思
How do you mean?
如果你不想继续下去
Well, if you wanted something else,
对你们的事业会是致命打击
that would be really bad for business.
你得吃点东西
You should eat.
蛇对夏娃也这么说
Said the snake to Eve.
吃你的苹果吧  世界不会就此终结
Eat your apple. The world won't end.
你得给你夫人打电话让她离开
You need to get on the phone and tell her to leave.
即便我打了她也不会听
She wouldn't listen to me even if I did.
她现在一门心思要为你说服这家伙
She's dead set on convincing this guy for your benefit.
必要的话  我会让保安护送她出来
I'll have the guards escort her out if necessary.
他们休想动我夫人一根手指
They will not lay a finger on my wife.
你其实更希望如此吧
You'd actually prefer that, wouldn't you?
这样你就能告诉全世界
So you could tell the world
我们拉着第一夫人的头发  把她拽了出来
we dragged the First Lady out by her hair.
我实在是越来越难以忍受你的多疑
I'm finding it more and more difficult to tolerate your paranoia.
我对你的谎言也一样
I could say the same of your lies.
我撒谎时  你绝不会发现
When I lie to you, you'll never know it,
而且肯定是有个好理由
and it will be for a good reason.
科里根可不算
Corrigan doesn't fall into that category.
我就不该邀请你来访问
I should never have invited you here.
你我可以协作  今天下午就是证明
You and I can work together. This afternoon is proof.
我就应该坚守我的立场
I would've been better off holding my ground.
然后逼我们通过决议案吗
And forcing us to pass the resolution?
联合国  我才不把他们放在心上
The United Nations? They mean nothing to me.
如果真是这样  你就会坚守立场了
If they meant nothing to you, you would have held your ground.
但你希望在国外和在国内一样受到尊敬
But you want to be respected abroad as much as you are at home.
而我是怀着敬意而来  维克多
And I came here out of respect, Viktor.
我对你的处境感同身受
And I sympathize with the situation you're in.
我们都深陷其中
That we're both in.
不要让迈克尔·科里根
Let's not let Michael Corrigan
决定国际形势的走向
dictate the course of nations.
我们至少讨论下
Can we at least discuss
如果由我发言应该怎么说
what a statement from me might look like?
你看上去精疲力竭
You look exhausted.
我在飞机上没怎么睡
I didn't sleep much on the plane, so...
你回去吧
You should go back.
你没必要跟我一起待在这里
There's no reason for you to be in here with me.
我不会走的
I'm not leaving.
你比我还固执呢
You're more stubborn than I am.
你为什么不让我帮你呢
Why won't you let me help you?
我的要求很明确
I've made my demands clear.
迈克尔  我告诉你如果你不肯
Michael, let me tell you what's going to happen
发表声明会发生什么吧
if you refuse to make this statement.
你谁都帮不了
You'll help no one.
事实上  其他那些跟你
In fact, life will get worse
一起被捕的人会陷入更糟的境地
for the others you were arrested with.
佩特罗夫会感到丢脸  会逮捕更多人
Petrov will feel embarrassed. He will arrest more people.
会通过更可怕的法律
He will pass worse laws.
他不会让一个美国的同性恋左右他的政策
He's not going to let some American homosexual dictate his policy.
此人十分无情
This man is ruthless.
你以为如果这事不成
You think he's gonna become reasonable suddenly
他就会突然讲理了吗
when all of this falls apart?
你太天真了
You're being naive!
而且你还让别人为你的天真付出代价
And you're letting other people suffer because of it.
别毁掉你一直以来的努力
Don't undo what you've fought so hard for.
你以为你能激我同意吗  你做不到
You think you can shame me. But you can't.
我是在告诉你实话
I'm giving you the truth.
我不管你对此有什么感受
I don't care how that makes you feel.
但帮自己个忙  听进去我的话
But do yourself the favor of hearing what I said.
-我听到了  -希望如此
- I heard you. - I hope so.
我不能背叛自己  那我成什么了
I can't betray myself. What would I be then?
政客  你本就是政客
You'd be a politician. And that's what you are.
让其他人去吼叫呐喊吧
Let the others do all the yelling and screaming.
你想要改变  就得学会妥协
You want change? Then learn how to compromise.
成熟一点  迈克尔
Be a fucking adult about this, Michael.
我得想想  好吗  我需要时间
I need to think. Okay? I need time.
飞机明天就起飞了
The plane leaves tomorrow.
你回去吧  我需要时间独自想想
You should go back. I need time to think alone.
-清空思绪  -你不走  我也不走
- Clear my head. - I'm not leaving here without you.
我需要时间
I need time!
你躺一会儿吧
Just... lie down for a little bit.
休息一下
Just get some rest.
-我不想再跟你争了  -好吧
- I just can't talk anymore. - Okay.
我躺会儿
Okay, I will.
就一会儿
For a few minutes.
谢谢
Thanks.
这病现在可以治的
There's treatment now.
最让我生气的
The thing that angers me the most
是我让她这么对我
is that I let her do this to me.
你对你前任也是这个感觉吗
Did you feel that way about your ex?
那痛苦能把你吞噬
The pain that just consumes you?
有一阵吧
For a while, yeah.
心情不好时还能感觉到
Still, on bad days.
她什么样
What was she like?
抱歉  你不非得...
Sorry, you don't have to...
没事  我不介意
No, I don't mind.
她...
She was...
她以前挺不容易
She'd had a tough life.
有很多负担  我之前也是
She had a lot of baggage. Which I did, too.
我们起初只是朋友  后来搬到一起住
We started out as friends and then we moved in together.
然后就发生了
And then it just happened.
我们相爱了
We fell in love.
我说不清
And I don't know, I guess...
跟她在一起  我觉得自己更强大了
I felt stronger with her.
我觉得她也有这种感觉
And I think she felt the same way.
或许是我天真
And I guess maybe it was naive,
但我以为我们携手前进  可以放下那些过去
but I thought that together, we could let go of all that baggage.
就一起做我们自己
Then we'd just be us.
那她为什么离开了
Well, why did she leave?
她说这一切太快了
She said everything was happening too quickly.
你之后再联络过她吗
Have you spoken to her... since?
没有  她再也不去团契了
Nope. She stopped coming to the fellowship.
我去过她公寓一次
I stopped by her apartment once,
房东说她走了
her landlord said she was gone.
你完全不知道她在哪吗
Just no idea where she is?
我们以前会躺在床上  幻想如果有选择
We used to lie in bed and fantasize about where we'd go
我们会去哪  巴黎  澳大利亚  廷巴克图
if we could go anywhere. Paris, Australia, Timbuktu.
瑞秋就这样  渴望远走高飞  我并不需要
That was Rachel, the far-off places. I didn't need that.
你想去哪
Where would you go?
希门尼斯山路
The Jimenez Trail.
在哪啊
Where is that?
新墨西哥州
New Mexico.
穿过整个州
Cuts across the whole state.
一路上有温泉  瀑布
It's got hot springs and waterfalls.
我们以前曾说要去  徒步
We used to say we'd go there, hike it,
找个好地方  建个小屋
find a good spot, build a cabin.
抱歉  不该净说我的事
I'm sorry, we shouldn't be talking about me.
是我问的
I asked.
茶闻着挺香
That tea smells good.
我也来杯好了
I think I'll have some, too.
可以
This looks good.
-每字每句吗  -当然
- You say every word. - Of course.
然后直接带他上飞机
And then you take him directly to the plane.
维克多  谢谢你
Viktor... thank you.
但是捷克共和国
But the Czech Republic,
所有导弹都要撤走  不光是部分撤离
I want all the missiles gone, not just a scale-back.
波兰可以留点做个样子  但仅此而已
You can keep something in Poland for show, but that's it.
同意
Agreed.
我们达成协议了吗
So, we have a deal?
包括我们讨论过的所有关于约旦河谷的事项
Including everything we discussed about the Jordan Valley.
是的  当然
Yes, of course.
那我们达成协议了
Then we have a deal.
天哪
Господи.
立刻把她带出去
Надо ее отсуда выводить.
快把他放下来  快  快
Спусти его скромно. Пошли, пошли!
走吧  安德伍德夫人
Come, Mrs. Underwood.
走吧  您不该待在这儿
Please. You shouldn't be here.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你想先休息下吗  换身衣服
Would you like to lie down for a bit? Change your clothes?
不  我上飞机再换吧
No, I can do that on the plane.
你直接去吧
Well, you go straight there.
我们还有新闻发布会要开
We have the press conference to do.
我该跟你一起  弗兰西斯
I should be with you, Francis.
我们能处理
We have that handled.
我想说点什么  抚慰他的家人
I'd like to say something. A few warm words to his family.
好的  当然可以
Yes. Yes, of course.
我也会表示惋惜  然后
I'll echo your sympathy and then...
然后说我今天本打算释放他
then say that I was planning on releasing him today.
我会感谢你的...大度
I'll thank you for your... your generosity.
整件事真是悲剧
How tragic this has been.
再提下约旦河谷
And then a few words about the Jordan Valley,
或者你想来宣布我们的协议吗
or if you'd prefer to announce our agreement.
不用  你说就行
No, no, it's fine if you do.
你介意让你手下
Would you... mind if your people
给我一份你声明的简稿吗
showed me a draft of your remarks?
当然  我马上让他们开始起草
Yes, I'll have them draft something right now.
你呢  安德伍德夫人
And yours, too, Mrs. Underwood?
好的  听你的
Yes. It's fine. Whatever you want.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
早上好
Good morning.
安德伍德夫人想先简单说几句
Mrs. Underwood would like to start by saying a few words.
如你们所知  迈克尔·科里根今天早上
As you all know, Michael Corrigan was found dead
被发现死在自己的牢房里
in his cell this morning.
他上吊自杀了
He had hung himself.
迈克尔和我昨天简单谈了一下
Michael and I spoke briefly yesterday.
他一直得到善待  也很感激佩特罗夫总统
He was being treated well and was grateful to President Petrov
即将批准释放他
for granting his imminent release.
我们不知道迈克尔自杀的原因
We don't know why... Michael chose to do what he did.
我们本都满心希望迈克尔今天能回家
We all wanted nothing more than for Michael to come home today
我们向他的家人和亲友
and we offer our heartfelt condolences
致以最衷心的哀悼
to his family and his loved ones.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你  安德伍德夫人
Thank you, Mrs. Underwood.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood?
我不单是昨天跟他谈过话
I didn't just speak to him yesterday,
事情发生时我也在场  睡着了
I was there when it happened, asleep.
他是用我的围巾上吊的
He hung himself with my scarf.
我知道迈克尔为什么决定结束自己的生命
I do know why Michael decided to take his own life:
因为他不想说谎
because he didn't want to lie.
我现在不能再用谎言玷污他
And I can't dishonor him by telling a lie now.
克莱尔
Claire...
我本想劝说他  让他承认他违了法
I was trying to convince him to say that he broke the law,
让他感谢佩特罗夫总统
to thank President Petrov.
但他拒绝了  因为他拒绝离开那里
But he refused, because he didn't want to leave
除非法律被废除
until the law was repealed.
除非那些因同样罪名被捕的俄罗斯人
Until the Russians who were arrested for the same crime
也得到释放
were also released.
迈克尔愿意为他的信念而死
Michael was willing to die for what he believed in.
-谢谢  安德伍德夫人  -他很勇敢
- Thank you, Mrs. Underwood. - He was brave.
-他的声音理应被听到  -够了
- And his voice deserves to be heard. - That's enough.
如果不是因为这不公的法律
If it weren't for this unjust law,
还有你们政府的无知  狭隘
and ignorance and intolerance of your government,
迈克尔也不会离开我们
Michael would still be with us.
你真可耻  总统先生
Shame on you, Mr. President.
我妻子过去这一天
My wife has been under a...
一直压力很大
great amount of stress these past 24 hours.
她显然还余惊未消
She's clearly in shock.
我向佩特罗夫总统和俄国人民道歉
My apologies to President Petrov and to the Russian people.
恕我失陪  我得去陪我妻子
If you'll excuse me, I need to be with her now.
-克莱尔  -别  弗兰西斯
- Claire. - Don't, Francis.
我必须跟他说话
It's imperative that I speak to him.
继续打  凯茜
Well, keep trying, Cathy.
如果佩特罗夫不接我电话
If Petrov won't get on the phone with me,
那我就跟布加耶夫谈
then I'll speak to Bugayev.
那就任何愿意跟我通话的人
Whoever will get on the phone with me, then.
好  谢谢
All right. Thank you.
您的咖啡  先生
Your coffee, sir.
谢谢  本
Thank you, Ben.
-总统先生  -待会儿的
- Mr. President. - Later.
我刚跟凯茜通完话  协议取消了
I just got off the phone with Cathy. The deal's off.
我们谈好的一切都推翻了
Everything we negotiated.
我们得讨论下一步
We have to discuss the next move.
我知道我做了什么  看起来是很冲动
I know what I did. It seemed impulsive,
-但并不是...  -事已至此  我们继续吧
- but it wasn't-- - It happened. Let's move on.
如果你想说什么  弗兰西斯
If you have something you would like to say, Francis...
我只想尽量减少损害
I just want to minimize the damage.
如果佩特罗夫不肯回头
If Petrov won't come around,
我们就得推进联合国的决议案了
we have to move forward with the resolution at the UN.
我们已经准备好了
We're prepared for that.
很好  谢谢  尽量睡会儿吧
Good. Thank you. Try to get some sleep.
你不是该在后面跟媒体在一起吗
Shouldn't you be in the back, with the press?
-我不是媒体  -你也不是工作人员
- I'm not press. - You're not staff either.
抱歉
My apologies.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood?
你做得对
You did the right thing.
我知道你很生气
I know you're angry.
你有权生气
You should be.
但我必须那么做
But I had to do it.
这算是道歉
Is this some sort of apology,
还是你想一吐为快
or you need to get something off your chest?
我希望你能努力去理解
I want you to try and understand.
理解
Understand?
-你所做的超出了...  -我知道
- What you did was beyond-- - I know.
你不只是第一夫人  大使
You're not only the First Lady, and an ambassador,
你也是我妻子
you're also my wife.
-什么顺序  -拜托  克莱尔
- In what order? - Oh, come on, Claire.
我所说的是为了他
I said what I said for him.
不是为我自己  不是为我们
Not for myself, not for us.
为了他  我们也不该做一份虚伪的声明
I felt we owed him more than a few false words.
你是要我原谅你  告诉你没关系吗
So you want me to forgive you? To say that it was okay?
-不  -因为我做不到
- No. - Because I can't do that.
我没这意思
I'm not asking you to.
那我们为什么还要讨论这个
Then why are we even discussing it?!
因为我想让你知道原因
Because I want you to know why.
我不在乎原因
I don't care why.
我不在乎你的原因是什么
I don't care what your reasons are.
没有任何原因
There is no reason that can possibly convince me
让你有权毁掉我们耗费数月推行的和平计划
that you should have sabotaged a peace plan we spent months on!
我犯了个政治错误
It was a political mistake.
是的  我承认  但如果我什么都不说
Yes, I admit that. But if I had said nothing,
他的死就毫无意义了
his death would have meant nothing.
不  不是死  他那不叫死
No. Not death. Don't give him that.
-是自杀  -不
- Suicide. - No.
无法否认的事情  我不会否认的
Something undeniable. I was not gonna try and deny it.
-我都不明白你什么意思  -如果你肯给我机会
- I don't even understand that. - If you'd give me a chance.
我已经给了你机会  休会任命
I gave you a chance with the recess appointment,
决议案  还有跟科里根谈
with the resolution, with handling Corrigan.
他别无选择  弗兰西斯  我们把他逼入绝境了
He didn't have a choice, Francis. We cornered him.
-他有选择  -在他看来没有
- He did have a choice. - Not in his mind.
没人逼他在莫斯科抗议
No one forced him to protest in Moscow.
我们也绝对没有让他
And we sure as hell didn't ask him
用你的围巾上吊自杀
to tie your scarf around his neck!
如果你跟他谈过
If you had spoken to him...
听听他的话
and heard what he had to say--
怎么  我就会豁然开朗吗
Oh, what, I would have had some moral epiphany?
-是的  你会的  -我不这么认为
- Yes, you would have. - I don't think so.
因为我是美国总统
Because I'm the President of the United States
我能分清孰轻孰重
and I can separate the big from the small.
他并不轻
He wasn't small.
他是个懦夫  我很高兴他死了
He was a coward and I'm glad he's dead.
他比你勇敢得多
He had more courage than you'll ever have.
你真要讨论勇敢吗  克莱尔
Do you really want to discuss courage, Claire?
因为任何人都可以自杀
Because anyone can commit suicide,
或是在摄像机前口无遮拦
or spout their mouth in front of a camera.
但你知道什么才叫真正的勇敢吗
But you wanna know what takes real courage?
无论内心有何感受  都能管住嘴巴
Keeping your mouth shut, no matter what you might be feeling.
形势如此严峻  仍能不乱阵脚
Holding it all together when the stakes are this high.
是我们杀了他  弗兰西斯
We're murderers, Francis.
不  不是的  这叫适者生存
No, we're not. We're survivors.
如果我们不能对这个勇敢的人表示敬意
If we can't show some respect for one brave man
而继续完成我们原本的计划
and still accomplish what we set out to do,
那我会对我们俩都很失望
then I'm disappointed in both of us.
我就不该任命你做大使
I should've never made you ambassador.
我就不该让你当上总统
I should've never made you president.
看什么看
What are you looking at?
今年二月  奥巴马的挚友  两次总统竞选团队的总军师  大卫·阿索罗
出版回忆录  披露奥巴马实际上一直都支持同性恋婚姻
但是在08年的时候因为顾及选票  而硬着头皮表示反对同性恋婚姻合法化
但是到了2012年大选前夕  奥巴马决定"立场出柜"
转变自己08年的态度  接受ABC电视台专访  公开支持同性婚姻合法化
在此之前  奥巴马通过同国会的谈判
废除了美国军中"不许出柜"的软性同性恋禁令
LGBT(同性  双性  变性)群体也是奥巴马两次总统选举中
最坚定的支持群体之一
有着基督教传统的美国社会  一度非常反对同性婚姻合法化
但近些年  主流民意已经发生很大变化
越来越多的人对同性恋权益表示支持
在奥巴马和最高法院的推动下  目前美国已有37个州承认同性婚姻合法